worldbookonline.com 2016-06-04

# Privacy Policy

Thank you for reviewing our Privacy Policy.  World Book, Inc. (“ **World Book** ,” “ **we** ,” “ **us** ” or “ **our** ”) operates and hosts World Book Online, accessible through [www](http://www.ebooks.worldbookonline.com/ "blocked::http://www.ebooks.worldbookonline.com/")[.worldbookonline.com](http://www.ebooks.worldbookonline.com/ "blocked::http://www.ebooks.worldbookonline.com/"), related mobile applications and other online programs (collectively, the “ **Online Services** ”), each of which may be subject to platform-specific additional terms.  By using our Online Services, you consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and subject to the terms of the World Book Terms of Use.

We operate and host the Online Services from the United States of America.  Access to the Online Services is restricted to individuals who have accepted our Terms of Use.  If you choose to access any of the Online Services from locations outside the United States of America, you do so at your own risk and subject to the laws of the United States of America which may differ from privacy laws in your state or home country, and you are responsible for compliance with any local laws.  By submitting your personal information to us or our agents through the use of the Online Services, you consent to the transfer of your personal information to any country and its use and disclosure in accordance with applicable U.S. federal and state laws and with this Privacy Policy.  You may not use or export anything (including information) from the Online Services in violation of U.S. export laws, regulations or the Terms of Use.

World Book is concerned about the privacy of information shared through the Online Services. We have created this Privacy Policy to let you know how World Book collects, uses and safeguards the information that is collected and used on the Online Services. Our privacy practices are guided by the United States' Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998, as well as data privacy laws in the United States and other applicable countries.  Children under thirteen (13) years of age should always check with their parents or guardians before entering information on any website, including the Online Services, and we encourage families to discuss their household guidelines regarding the online sharing of personal information.

It is our policy to protect your personal information and to use it only in accordance with this Privacy Policy.  This Privacy Policy only governs our use and disclosure of information collected through the Online Services, and works in conjunction with the Terms of Use, but does not modify or supersede them.  Using the Online Services is voluntary, and by accessing or using the Online Services, you: (i) acknowledge that you have read and understood this Privacy Policy; (ii) agree that your access and use of the Online Services are subject to this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use; and (iii) consent to our collection and use of your non-personal and personally identifiable information as described in this Privacy Policy, as updated or revised from time to time.  At all times, we reserve the right to disclose any information, including personally identifiable information, to comply with any applicable law, regulation, legal process or government request; to protect our rights and our property (including, without limitation) in the event of transfer of control of the company or substantially all of its assets), or during emergencies when safety is at risk, or for credit fraud protection and risk reduction purposes. 

**Modifications** **.**

World Book may change this Privacy Policy at any time, consistent with the terms set forth in the Terms of Use, by posting the changed or amended Privacy Policy on the Online Services and updating the “Effective Date” set forth below. Your continued use of the Online Services following the posting of any changes to this Privacy Policy will signify your acceptance of any such changes or amendments.  Therefore, we encourage you to check our Privacy Policy whenever you use our Online Services to see if it has been updated since your last visit. 

**Privacy Policy Limited to the Online Services.**

This Privacy Policy is specific to the Online Services.  This Privacy Policy applies only to the Online Services and does not apply to activities that are "offline" or unrelated to the Online Services, including activities occurring on other websites that we operate. You should note that different privacy policies may apply to other parts of World Book’s web presence. 

**Types of Information Collected** **.**

Several types of data are collected from you when you visit our Online Services, including: (i) personally identifiable information; and (ii) non-personal information.  Certain types of data are specifically NOT collected, including financial information.

_Personally Identifiable Information_.  We may ask you to provide personally identifiable information (“ **PII** ”) when you use the Online Services, which may include:

  * your first name;
  * user name and password (for account administration);
  * email address, only if you would like us to use it to retrieve for you your login information in the event you have forgotten it; 
  * answer to security question, so we can retrieve for you your password in the event you have forgotten it; and
  * device ID, including IP address.

This information can be gathered when you send us feedback or an email, when you disclose your email address as stated previously, when you register for certain services, when we set cookies, or directly in response to inquiries on the Online Services.

Also, we may collect information on your preferences based upon searches that you conduct through the Online Services.  In all such cases you choose whether to provide us with PII; however, certain portions of the Online Services may not be available to you if you do not provide the information requested.  By providing such information, you consent to our collection and use of it, as described in this Privacy Policy; however, World Book does not require you to disclose more information than is reasonably necessary to use a feature or functionality of the Online Services as a condition of participation. 

_Non-Personal Information_. We automatically collect certain anonymous data regarding usage of the Online Services. The anonymous data we collect may include but is not limited to such information as:

  * The name of the internet domain you used to access the internet;
  * The IP address of the Online Services from which you linked to our Online Services;
  * The date and time you accessed our Online Services;
  * The type of web browser you are using; and
  * The pages on the Online Services that you visited.

This information (" **Non-Personal Information** ") does not personally identify users, by itself or in combination with other information. We use this Non-Personal Information to monitor the effectiveness of the Online Services and to consider potential changes to improve the user experience. Non-Personal Information may be collected through cookies. For more detailed information on cookies, please refer to the “Use of Cookies” section below.

_Other Information NOT Collected_.  Our services and your use of the Online Services do not require you to disclose, nor require us to request or collect, any credit card or other financial information, or any other personally identifiable information not described above, such as last name, home contact information, date of birth, Social Security number, or other similar non-public information. We do not request, solicit or intend to collect any such information and you should not disclose, enter or upload any such information on the Online Services.  If we discover that such information was disclosed by you, we will exercise commercially reasonable efforts to delete such information; however, we are not liable for any consequences relating to such disclosures of information.

_Personal Information from Children_.  We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of thirteen (13) without the consent of their parents or guardians. For users less than thirteen (13) years of age, your parent or guardian can review the PII that we collect, ask to have it deleted and refuse to allow any further collection or use of such PII. For more information, or to exercise such rights, please contact World Book using the contact information provided below.

**Use and Disclosure of Information Collected** **.**

Our use and disclosure of certain information varies with respect to the type of information collected, including: (i) PII; and (ii) Non-Personal Information.

_Personally Identifiable Information_.  We use PII collected through the Online Services in conjunction with products and services offered and to respond to your requests for information on products or services. Additionally, we may use your email address to communicate with you regarding your account information only; accordingly, such communications do not constitute marketing.  We may also combine such information with similar information for other users to create aggregate reports, which may be shared with your school, institution or other organizational subscriber and utilized internally by World Book.  In all cases, information included within such aggregate reports is not individually identifiable.  

World Book will not sell your PII to any third parties for marketing purposes.  Though we make every effort to preserve your privacy, disclosure of your information to third parties for non-marketing purposes may occur in certain situations such as: (i) responding to a subpoena, court order or other such request; (ii) responding to a law enforcement agency's request or as otherwise required by law; and (iii) providing your information to a third party if we file for bankruptcy, or there is a transfer of the assets or ownership in connection with proposed or consummated corporate reorganizations, such as mergers, acquisitions, or sales of business units. In all such instances, we will take the utmost care to disclose only that information which is necessary and appropriate under the circumstances.  Additionally, we may share personal information with third-party vendors who assist us in performing internal functions necessary to operate our business. We require our third-party vendors to keep such information confidential and to only use the information for the purpose it was provided.

_Non-Personal Information_.  We use the Non-Personal Information collected through the Online Services for statistical purposes and for improving the functionality of the Online Services. In general, this information is used internally but we may, from time to time, engage a third party’s software or services to assist us with these analyses. In those limited cases, disclosure of this information to a third party is necessary; however, the data remains anonymous at all times. 

**Visibility of Your Personally Identifiable Information.**  

Information which you have chosen to publish on our Online Services may be viewed by other users of the Online Services.  We are not able to monitor, control, or prevent others from copying, modifying, transmitting, sharing or otherwise further disseminating the information that you have posted in the interactive areas of the Online Services.   We do not ensure, warrant or guarantee the security of any information that is disclosed online, so you should consider carefully whether you are comfortable sharing such information in light of the risks. ** **

**Use of Cookies** **.**  

Cookies are small bits of data cached or stored on your computer based on internet activity. We may use cookies to monitor individual activity in aggregate to improve the Online Services and provide features that are tailored to your needs. The information we gather may include IP address, user language, the operating system, browser type, the presence/absence of “flash” plug-ins, screen resolution, connection type, and information that identifies the cookie. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually change your browser settings to prevent this. If you disable cookies, your ability to use some features of the Online Services may be limited. 

We also use session cookies when you visit the Online Services. Session cookies are active only during the period you are logged on to the Online Services, and are removed when you leave. They help us track the sections of the Online Services that you use to allow us to make improvements in keeping with observed user preferences. This information helps us identify content and services that may be of interest to our users as we work to make further improvements to the Online Services.

**Linked Online Services.**

We may provide links on the Online Services to other sites of interest; however, we do not review or endorse the content of these sites, and are not responsible for that content or the privacy policies of websites to which the Online Services link. If you provide any information to such third parties, different rules regarding the collection and use of your personal information may apply. We strongly suggest you review such third party's privacy policies and terms of use before providing any data to them. You should contact these entities directly if you have any questions about their use of the information that they collect. 

**Security; No Liability.**

World Book has implemented multiple tiers of security measures to help protect against the risk of loss, misuse and alteration of any information under World Book's control. PII provided to World Book is encoded using commercially reasonable technology, consistent with industry standard encryption protocols that protects data as it travels over the internet, provided your browser supports it. Nevertheless, such security measures may not prevent all loss, misuse or alteration of information on the Online Services, and World Book and its third-party licensors are not responsible for any damages or liabilities relating to any such security failures. 

**Your California Privacy Rights.**

California Civil Code Section 1798.83, also known as the "Shine The Light" law, permits users who are California residents to request and obtain from us once a year, free of charge, information about the personal information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year. If applicable, this information would include a list of the categories of personal information that was shared and the names and addresses of all third parties with which we shared information in the immediately preceding calendar year. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request in writing to:

World Book, Inc.  
233 North Michigan Avenue, Suite 2000  
Chicago, IL 60601  
Attention: Customer Service

**Questions** **.**

If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy or the use of your information, or to modify or update any information we have received, please contact us through the Online Services or by physical or electronic mail addressed to:

World Book, Inc.  
180 N LaSalle St. Suite 900  
Chicago, IL 60601  
Attention: Customer Service

Email: [help@worldbook.com](mailto:help@worldbook.com "blocked::mailto:help@worldbook.com")

Effective Date: March 18, 2014
